Every generation has a story.
Star Wars: The Force Awakens is a adventure, action,
science fiction film directed by J.J. Abrams.
Thirty years after defeating the Galactic Empire, Han Solo and his allies face a
new threat from the evil Kylo Ren and his army of Stormtroopers.
Han Solo, played by Harrison Ford.
Luke Skywalker, played by Mark Hamill.
General Leia Organa, played by Carrie Fisher.
Kylo Ren / Ben Solo, played by Adam Driver.
Rey, played by Daisy Ridley.
Finn, played by John Boyega.
Star Wars: The Force Awakens (also known as Star Wars: Episode VII – The Force Awakens) is a
2015 American epic space opera film produced, co-written, and directed by J.
The sequel to Return of the Jedi (1983), it is the first installment of the Star Wars
sequel trilogy and chronologically the seventh film of the "Skywalker Saga".
Set thirty years after Return of the Jedi, The Force Awakens follows Rey, Finn, Poe Dameron, and Han Solo's search for Luke Skywalker and their fight in the
Resistance, led by General Leia Organa and veterans of the Rebel Alliance, against Kylo Ren and the First Order, a successor to the Galactic Empire.
The film stars Harrison Ford, Mark Hamill, Carrie Fisher, Adam Driver, Daisy Ridley, John Boyega, Oscar Isaac,
Lupita Nyong'o, Andy Serkis, Domhnall Gleeson, Anthony Daniels, Peter Mayhew, and Max von Sydow.
Work on a seventh entry in the "Skywalker Saga" commenced after the
Walt Disney Company's acquisition of Lucasfilm in 2012.
The film is the first Star Wars film to not extensively involve franchise creator George
Lucas, who only served as a creative consultant in the early stages of production.
The Force Awakens was produced by Abrams, his longtime collaborator
Bryan Burk, and Lucasfilm president Kathleen Kennedy.
Abrams and Lawrence Kasdan, co-writer of the original trilogy films The Empire Strikes Back
(1980) and Return of the Jedi, rewrote an initial script by Michael Arndt.
John Williams, composer for the previous episodic
films, returned to compose the score.
Principal photography began in April 2014 and concluded the following November.
Filming took place on sets at Pinewood Studios in England, and on
location mainly in Abu Dhabi, Iceland, and Ireland.
On a budget of $447 million, it is the fourth-most expensive film ever made.
The Force Awakens premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on December 14, 2015, and was released in the United States on December
18, making it the first live action Star Wars film to be distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
A critical and commercial success, the film grossed $2.07 billion worldwide, breaking various box office records and becoming the highest-grossing
film in the United States and Canada, the highest-grossing film of 2015, and the third-highest-grossing film at the time of its release.
It was nominated for five awards at the 88th Academy
Awards and received numerous other accolades.
The film was followed by The Last Jedi (2017) and The Rise of
Skywalker (2019), rounding out the Star Wars sequel trilogy.
The film explores themes of android, spacecraft, space opera, absurd.
The tone is thought_provoking.